Good morning everybody.
Emmanuel! (God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Titilola Siphiwe Labode.
I'm from Zimbabwe. I'm half Nigerian and half Zimbabwean.
The woman beside me is my mother, Honourable Doctor Ruth Labode from Zimbabwe as well.
I will start my testimony with the crisis.
I went to university in England in 2004.
I picked up certain habits that affected me.
These habits included smoking and drinking.
I used to smoke and drink for eight years.
It was quite bad as it wasn't one or two cigarettes a day. I used to smoke twenty cigarettes a day.
My parents used to send me money for my tuition, my accommodation and my welfare.
They never wanted me to have a job while I was studying.
They wanted me to complete my studies without working.
But because my smoking and drinking habits were quite expensive in the UK,
I secretly got myself a job to support my drinking and smoking habits.
It was really bad because I passed with a 2.2 degree in BSc Accounting
but I spent most of my time out.
I would go out everyday. I would be in the club smoking and drinking.
It was just by the grace of God that nothing bad happened to me.
But I wasn't in good health.
I was very skinny and had bad skin.
I just wasn't healthy.
After a while, my parents begged me to come back home to Zimbabwe.
I used to refuse, saying that I was fine. I was ok in England -
working and being independent.
The people that I surrounded myself with were also smokers and drinkers.
So to me it was a normal life.
I would say that this is normal life here.
You are just in Africa and backwards.
You don't understand.
Eventually my mom and dad convinced me to move back to Zimbabwe where I grew up.
They brought me to The SCOAN in June 2014.
When I came to The SCOAN, I was placed in the prayer line.
I received Morning Water and was also blessed.
The man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua laid his hand on me.
When he laid his hand on me,
I felt this electricity going through my body.
Then after that, he didn't touch me. He just moved his hand and I fell on the floor.
I was conviced that someone had pulled me down.
Because afterwards I went to my mom and said,
"Mom, somebody pulled me down so that I could fall".
And then she said, "No, you were by yourself", although I was conviced otherwise.
But then when I was at home, I watched the video and saw that there was no one standing next me.
I went back home and tried to go back to my habit of smoking.
I was trying to force the issue because to me it was cool to be having a cigarette and a drink when being out.
But when I started smoking, I started feeling sick.
I would feel like I had a lot of phlegm and mucus in my throat.
I would feel tired and dizzy.
It just wasn't going well with my body anymore.
So eventually, I started cutting down and then stopped smoking.
Whilst I used to smoke, drink and go out in England,
I used to have a lot of bad dreams.
I would dream of snakes.
I would dream of having intercourse.
I would have bad dreams, dreaming of scorpions, spiders and all sorts.
After my deliverance at The SCOAN, I had a dream about Prophet T.B. Joshua.
He actually came to me in the dream.
I was holding a cigarette in my hand like this.
He came to me and pulled it out of my mouth and broke it in half.
I believe that that was where my deliverance started, from that dream where he actually visited me.
I want to give glory to the Lord because I am now a new creation in Christ and I am much healthier and happier.
Hallelujah.
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
Before when I would try to stop smoking on my own,
I would stop for three months.
But then if someone was smoking in front of me, I would follow them and inhale the smoke
because I would be craving for it.
It would be the same with drinking as I would try to stop drinking
but I would then secretly buy myself a bottle of wine and go to my room.
But then I was just deceiving myself because at the end of the day I was still drinking
and God knew that I was still drinking.
But after the man of God touched me,
even if someone would smoke next to me, I would actually move away as it is now like poison to me.
I don't want the smell of smoke next to me.
Even with alcohol, I no longer crave for it.
Before, I would crave for it and had to have a glass of red wine every day.
It was a must. My mouth just wouldn't feel right without it.
But now, I don't even think about alcohol.
I'm happy and fresh.
I'm a new creation.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus!
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
Now, we want you to paint a clearer picture of how bad the situation was
when you were having this addiction to smoking and drinking.
What are some of those terrible moments that you find difficult to forget
when you were having this problem?
I will give you a couple of experiences that I had that were very bad.
I was out with my friends and I got very drunk.
I started vomiting in public.
My friends wanted to stay out and didn't care about how I was feeling.
So I spent the night in the club toilet being sick and vomiting.
The last terrible experience I had was when I came back to Zimbabwe.
I came back with that lifestyle because I was from England.
I continued it in Zimbabwe.
I went out. I drank a lot. I smoked 20 cigarettes that night.
When I got home, I was so dizzy.
I couldn't walk.
The door of the car was opened and I came crawling out of my car.
We have dogs at home and the situation was so bad that they were crawling beside me to the front door.
That is where my mother was and she looked at me in disgust.
When I think about it now, I feel sad.
But at the time, I would be annoyed at her and think, "What is her problem?
This is how I have always lived my life. She can't just try and change me".
That was my attitude before.
I didn't understand why she was trying to stop me from what I wanted to do
because to me that was normal.
When I look back at it, I feel sad and it is heart breaking.
One wastes so much time and spends so much money on things that just destroy your body.
When the Lord God gives you life and gives you Jesus, it is all that you need.
So I'm just grateful.
Hallelujah! Let's clap for Jesus Christ!
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
You said that all this while you were smoking and drinking,
what were you doing and how were you able to source for money
in order to keep us these bad habits?
As I mentioned earlier, I went to England to study at university.
My parents did not want me to work but to rather focus on my studies.
But because of my habits, that they were not aware of,
I went and got a part-time job.
I was working in a call centre while I was at university.
I used the money that they sent me to buy cases of cigarettes.
Especially at the airport when returning from a visit to Zimbabwe where cigarettes are very cheap,
I would buy cases of cigarettes and my mom wouldn't know.
She had no idea. In Africa when a child is misbehaving like that,
it makes the parent look bad.
But I didn't care. I would be saying that this was my addiction, my habit and my right.
I would buy cases of cigarettes and when I got to England,
I would smoke Marlboro and Marlboro cigarettes are very expensive.
Those are the ones that I wanted.
It left me broke all the time.
My dad even gave me his credit card one time
because he thought he was being considerate to his daughter and he loves me.
But he didn't know that I was supporting my bad habit with his money.
And now all of this is over?
Yes, all things of the past. I have found God now so I'm happy.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus one more time!
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
This is me while at university on a night out with my friends.
If you look closely, you will see that I'm holding a cigarette in my hand.
That's us in the club. We were just having drinks and cigarettes.
Ok. Point to yourself in the picture.
That's me in the middle.
Ok.
Over there. That is a cigarette.
If I zoom in for you, you can see the cigarette in my hand.
Ok.
You can also see my friends having cigarettes. We were all smokers.
We were all into the same.
That is another picture of me at a house party in summer time in England.
Where are you in the picture?
I was at a place called Grimsby. That is me over there.
Wow.
That is me lying down, holding a cigarette yet again.
And you can see the box on my lap.
If you look closely on my lap, you can see a box of cigarettes there.
That was my habit, that was my life.
It wasn't good.
To God be the glory! Now old things have passed away, all things have become new, right?
Yes.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
As the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, says, "When Jesus Christ enters our life,
He puts an end to our past and gives birth to our future".
Today, we thank God Almighty for the life of our sister
who has been delivered from her past life of smoking and drinking
and now she is a new creation in Christ Jesus.
Old things have passed away.
Glory be to God in the highest!
Emmanuel! (God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
By the grace of God, I am Honourable Doctor Ruth Labode,
a member of parliament in Zimbabwe.
I actually urged my daugher to give this testimony.
Not so much about her testimony but as a message to parents.
We work hard every day.
We chase money. We chase money like we are chasing the wind
because we want our children to live well.
We then send them abroad
without preparing them for the evil that is in the world.
We think because we can pay for the school fees
and the child passes the exams, that is it. That is not it.
When the child is not ready, the devil is waiting for the child somewhere in hell or in Liverpool.
The child is not prepared as the parents have not taken their child to God.
You have not taken your child to God because you yourself are a lukewarm Christian.
That is not important to you.
Yet, that is the most important thing and to prepare your child for what they will face in the world.
I believe it is wrong for us parents.
I know for sure.
What was important to me before was that my husband and I have paid the school fees.
Then we would phone and follow up on whether the child had passed the exams.
We didn't know that in the meantime the child was decaying.
The child was just dying a natural death in real life.
Yes, by the grace of God, they are passing the exams.
But what is to become of them in the future, that certificate may be useless.
I'm really urging parents.
We need to take our children to God. Especially when they are young.
We shouldn't just take them to church
because I took them to church but they were just playing around in church,
going to Sunday School and doing nothing.
After that we would go to KFC and then go home.
We didn't even discuss what we heard in church.
So it was a religious approach to things.
That religious approach is what caused her to not go to any church service
over the four to seven years she was in the UK.
She never learnt anything because her Sunday school was a nursery school.
Whilst I as the mother was attending the church service, she was playing.
So what I'm asking parents to know is that this is a terrible world.
Let's be careful and protect our children.
It is not by our strength but by taking them the person who gave them to you in the first place.
The gift is from Jesus, He's the one who gave them in the first place.
I will take you to Matthew 7:16-20 where it is said that a mango cannot beget a pineapple.
It means the people to blame for these children
or in other words, when you see your child misbehaving, look at yourself.
That is your mirror. That is you.
So what I am trying to say is that we should blame ourselves for what has become of our children.
My husband and I have blamed ourselves
because for sure, we were in the world,
even whilst we were doing some religious activities on Sundays.
But the truth is we were in the world.
So what did we pass on to our children? The worldly things.
Later when my daughter came back to Zimbabwe, I did not know she was smoking.
She used to sneak out during the night to the garden and smoke. Then, she came back into the house.
We thought all was well.
The day I started seeing her drinking habit getting worse was when I knew I was in trouble.
I started pumping her with Morning Water.
Sometimes she would be sleeping on her bed and I would go in her room.
I would spray the room, spray her and I would pray.
I would pray and say, "God, please, I have failed. I'm handing over this child to you.
You gave me this child. Redeem this child from this habit".
So when we came and the child was finally delivered, I found joy.
I found joy because she is now actually a lay preacher at our church.
For me that is actually extraordinary, comparing it with where she is coming from.
Wow! Put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
Hon. Dr Ruth Labode & Daughter - Deliverance testimony
Were you with her at the prayer line section where the man of God prayed for her?
Tell us - what happened?
I was with her at the prayer line. It was herself, the dad and I.
When the man of God just waved his hand, she fell.
In fact, I was worried that she was going to be injured.
She fell down and in the meantime I also fell to one side and my husband to another.
But when we stood up, she said something very interesting.
She said, "Mummy, someone pulled me down. I didn't fall".
I said, "No. Even the man of God didn't touch you.
He just waved his hand and you fell on your own.
And that was it".
There was a time we came and there was an all night prayer here.
That Friday she vomitted.
She used to have a nose ring and it popped out.
Maybe those were signs that her body was not clean.
There were a lot of things that weren't supposed to be there. I don't know.
We took it lighty and thought it was deliverance and we went home.
I'm so glad and grateful to God as God has been kind to us.
One by one He is dealing with us as a family.
Amen. Put your hands together for Jesus!
Hon. Dr Ruth Labode & Daughter - Deliverance testimony
Thank you, mama. Thank you for that wonderful word of advice to parents.
We would like to listen to your word of advice now as a youth.
Please, we want you to address the youth all over the world
concerning this smoking, drinking and other forms of addiction
that actually tarnish the future of the youth today and thank God you are delivered from it.
So what do you want to tell them?
Emmanuel to all the youth all over the world!
First of all, I want to encourage you to know and understand your Bible.
Seek first the Kingdom of God and then everything else will follow.
Do not surround yourself with people who are of the world.
I started smoking becase I was imitating my friends who were smokers
but I ended up overtaking them, smoking more cigarettes than they were.
You need to surround yourself with people of God - people of the same mission.
Listen to your parents.
When you go to church, don't go because you have to go.
Find it in your heart, pray to God and ask Him to open up your heart and make you have hunger for His Word.
Ask God to show Himself to you.
Ask Him to make you understand. The Holy Spirit should guide you and be your teacher.
It's important.
For me, it was my environment, the people around me.
At university, there were people who were Christians. But to me, they were boring.
In the world it is not all about being liked by other people.
It is about doing what is right for God.
That is what you need to do. Because eventually you are going to hear about God.
Eventually you are going to know and realise that what you are doing is bad.
So there is no point wasting years, money or time on things that will just kill you faster
because God has given us the gift of life.
If you walk the path of righteousness, you have a longer life.
If you walk the path of sin, your days are numbered.
So to all the youth - it is not worth it.
Listen to your parents, come back to God
and surround yourself with good people.
The Bible is your key, your guide, your map and everything.
You should know your Bible, understand it and do what the Bible says. Don't just read it and be a pharisee.
Do what the Bible says - that is the main thing. Thank you.
Thank you very much. Let's clap for Jesus Christ!
Miss Titilola Labode & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
Thank you for that wonderful word of advice to the youth all over the world.
That is a food for thoughts because the Bible says that bad friends are epidemics.
Wayward friends are epidemics.
Bad companies corrupt good manners.
So wherever we find ourselves - on the campus, at work, school, anywhere -
we must not be too quick to trust
and we must not follow bad companies that will lead us to a wayward life.
And now that you have been set free, remember that Jesus Christ has delivered you
so that you might follow Him.
We now want to encourage you to make the Word of God the standard for your life
and as you do so, the blessings of God Almighty will continue to unfold in your life
and your future is guaranteed in Jesus' name!
Amen. Thank You, Jesus!
Thank you.